A Guide to the Theodore Shedlovsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA130
Rockefeller Archive Center
Theodore Shedlovsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1923-1980, bulk 1930-1976
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Shedlovsky, Theodore
FA130
19 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Theodore Shedlovsky (1898-1976), a physical chemist, focused his work on applying the techniques of physical chemistry to the study of biological processes. Shedlovsky was born on October 29, 1898 in St. Petersburg, Russia. He came to the United States in 1908, receiving his B.S. (1918) and Ph. D. (1925) in physical chemistry from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
In 1927 Shedlovsky joined the staff at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research as an assistant in the laboratory of Duncan A. MacInnes, a former professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Shedlovsky and MacInnes (later joined by Lewis G. Longsworth) were the primary members of a research group studying the physical chemistry of electrolytic solutions. Their work included examining the thermodynamic properties of electrolytic solutions, conductance, diffusion and electrophoresis. Shedlovsky focused his efforts on the field of conductance.
During his time at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (became Rockefeller University in 1965) Shedlovsky was also involved in collaboration with colleagues in the examination of bio-chemical systems. While at Rockefeller, Shedlovsky became an associate in 1929, and a member and professor in 1956.
Shedlovsky was involved in numerous non-scientific activities connected to the campus community. A great lover of music, Shedlovsky founded the Rockefeller University Concerts in 1958. In 1965 Shedlovsky was also instrumental in the founding of the Rockefeller Children's School. The school was created for children ages 3 to 7 whose parents were faculty, staff or students at the University.
Shedlovsky was a fellow of the New York Academy of Sciences from 1942 to 1960. He also served as vice president. Shedlovsky was also a member of the National Academy of Sciences, the American Chemical Society, and the American Association for the Advancement of Science. In 1969 Shedlovsky became emeritus at Rockefeller University and in 1975 received an honorary Doctor of Science degree from the University.
Theodore Shedlovsky died on November 5, 1976 following an extended illness.
Arrangement note
Arranged in alphabetical order, in chronological order & subject-based.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 Sh34
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Biochemistry; Biology -- Research; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Chemistry; Electrophoresis; New York Academy of Sciences; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Shedlovsky, Theodore
- Biographical, 1923-1980; 1; 0.2 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes biographical information related to Theodore Shedlovsky including obituaries. Also includes bibliographical information of Shedlovsky's published works, poems collected by Shedlovsky, invitations and postcards. Also includes photographs of Shedlovsky and others including signed portraits of colleagues.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged by subject.
  - Biographical material, including obituaries (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal Material (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - Portraits (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Portraits of others (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous I, folder 1 to 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous II, folder 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Subject Files, 1938-1976; 2; 4.2 Cubic Feet
  Includes primarily correspondence both personal and professional. Also includes: files on the New York Academy of Sciences; conference related materials; notes; newspaper clippings; photos; published reports, journal articles and catalogs; poetry and speeches.
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - A (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Accascina, F. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American-Soviet Science Society, 1946; folder 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American-Soviet Science Society, folder 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - [Annual Review of Physical Chemistry] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - [Austria] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - [Ba-Bi] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - [Bl-Bu] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bagarotti, Cornelia - correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Biophysical Society (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - [Bogdanovic, Sinisa] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - [Bronk, Detlev W.] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - [Brown, Alfred S. & Burch, George E.] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - [Ca-Coh] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - [Col-Cox] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - [Ca-Ch] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - [Coh-Con] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - [Challenge for Survival] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - [Circuit Diagrams Bridge] (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - [Columbia University] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical String Instruments, 1968 May 24; folder 1 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical String Instruments - RSVPs, folder 2 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical String Instruments - Photos, folder 3 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - [Consumers Technical Institute], folder 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - C.T.I. [Consumers Technical Institute] - Shedlovsky (President), folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - [Contents of the Reprint Library] (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - [Correspondence: Catherine ___ to Shedlovsky], 1969 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Lab budget & other (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re: Seminars (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - [Daggett-du Vigneaud] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - [Debye, Peter J.W. & Peter P. - Correspondence], folder 1 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - [Debye, Peter J.W. & Peter P. - Correspondence], folder 2 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - [Debye, Peter J.W. & Peter P. - Correspondence], folder 3 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - [Dermatology Foundation] (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [Eder-Evans] (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [Eigen-Electrochemical] (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - [Edelman, Gerald M.] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Electrophoresis Apparatus Album (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - [Fajans-Fruton] (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - [Fankuchen, I.] (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - [Financial Records-Notebook], 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Florentine Art & Artists (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Foam and Dishwash Evaluation (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - [Fulbright Scholars], 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fuoss, Raymond, folder 1 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fuoss, Raymond, folder 2 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Fuoss, Raymond, folder 3 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - [Galati-Guttman] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - [Goeffredi, Mario] (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Grants, folder 1 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - [Grants], folder 2 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Grants, folder 3 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - [Grants], folder 4 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - [Grants], folder 5 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - [Gray, Harry B.], folder 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [Gray, Harry B.], folder 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - [(Horace) Gregory Award], 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - [Hall-Hutten] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - [Hechter, Oscar] (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - [Heidelberger, Michael] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - [Hiatt, Caspar W.] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - [Horsfall, Frank L.] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - [Huddleson, I. Forest] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - [Inové-Ives] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Isotope Committee, 1948-1957 1965-1968; folder 1 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Isotope Committee, 1955; folder 2 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Isotope Committee, folder 3 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - [Jacobethal-Joyner] (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - [Janz, George J.], folder 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - [Janz, George J.], folder 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - [Journals, Chemistry] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - [Journal of Physical Chemistry] (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - [Kallet-Kilgore] (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - [Kirk-Kunitz] (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - [Kirkwood, John G.] (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - [Klotz, Irving M. & Kolin, Alexander] (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Kogbetliantz, E. ["Note on Education & Learning"] (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - [Lamb-Lord & Taylor] (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - [La Mer, Victor K.] (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Leeds & Northrup Company Catalog (and miscellaneous lab notes) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - [Leonard, John E.-Beckman Instruments, Inc.] (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - [Lowenhaupt, Benjamin] (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - [Ma-Murphy] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - [Manning, Gerald S.] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - [The Medical Letter] (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - [Miner, Roy Waldo] (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - [Miscellaneous], 1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, post cards (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (oil damaged), 1984 June (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence and notes] (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence and reprints] (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, reprints and data (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous notes - (H₂O-CH₃OH at 35°) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - [Musher, Jeremy I.] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - [MacFadyen, Douglas A.], folder 1 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - [MacFadyen, Douglas A.], folder 2 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - [MacFadyen, Douglas A.], folder 3 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - [MacFadyen, Douglas A.], folder 4 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - [MacInnes, Duncan A.] (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - [McLeod-McHale] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - [National-Nobel] (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - [National Academy of Sciences - Dr. David Mauzerall], folder 1 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - N.A.S. [National Academy of Sciences] - Papers - Annivers. (lectures), folder 2 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - [National Academy of Sciences], folder 3 of 6 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [National Academy of Sciences], folder 4 of 6 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - [National Academy of Sciences], folder 5 of 6 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [National Academy of Sciences], folder 6 of 6 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship - Science Committee Minutes and Bulletin, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - [National Institutes of Health] (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - [National Research Council] (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - [New York Academy of Sciences] (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - [New York Heart Association] (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "New Yorker Meeting" [regarding the Special Subcommittee on National Security of the Committee on Un-American Activities], 1948 March 11 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - [Noyes, W. Albert Jr.] (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - [Ober-Owen] (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Donald E. Olins - Poetry (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - [Onsager, Lars] (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 1 of 9 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 2 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 3 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 4 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 5 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 6 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 7 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 8 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - [Osterhout, W.J.V. & Marian Irwin ("Ikki")], folder 9 of 9 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - [Page-Proskauer] (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Phillips, R.A. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - [Physical Chemistry Committee] (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - [Physical Chemistry Seminars], folder 1 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - [Physical Chemistry Seminars], folder 2 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - [Poems - author unknown] (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - [Postal Savings Stamps] (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Posthumous correspondence (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Proposal Evaluation (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - [Public Health Service Applications] (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - [Rago-Rule] (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Recommendations (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - [Record Book - Dr. MacInnes], 1963 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - [Rockefeller, Peggy (Mrs. David)] (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - RU Budget - Memoranda (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - RU Budget - Requisitions (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - RU Budget - Telephone charges (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - RU Effort Reports (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - [Rukeyser, Muriel] (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - [Sabin - Soloviev] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - [Spero - Szilard] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - [Scatchard, George] (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Science & the Modern World (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - [Seitz, Frederick] (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - [Shedlovsky, Beatrice] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - [Shedlovsky, Richard] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - [Shedlovsky, T. - Annual Reports], 1953-1961 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - [Shedlovsky, T. - Articles & Reprints] (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - [Shedlovsky, T. - Data & Reprints] (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - [Shedlovsky, T. - Personal Correspondence], folder 1 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - [Shedlovsky, T. - Personal Correspondence] (mementos), folder 2 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - [Shedlovsky, T. - Olin Spivey] (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Subject Reference Notebook (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - [Sulfates], 1944 1951-1963; folder 1 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - [Sulfates], 1957-1963; folder 2 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - [Sulfates], 1938 1958-1963; folder 3 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - [Sulfates], 1959; folder 4 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - [Taylor-Tyler] (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - [Takeyama, Naokata] (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - [Theses], 1960 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Trieste Symposium on Electrolytes ["Papers' Abstracts"] Shedlovsky abstract p. 21, folder 1 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - [Trieste Symposium on Electrolytes], folder 2 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - [Troshin, A.S. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - [Uhlig-USSR] (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - [vanDyke-Viviani] (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Vacation Policy - RU (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - [Waksman-Weigl] (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - [Weiss-Wynne-Jones] (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - [Wang, Jui H.] (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - [Weissberger, A.] (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - [Weiner, Norbert] (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - [Wolfe, Lester] (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Yale University - Andrew Patterson (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - [Yip-Young] (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - [YMHA (Young Men's Hebrew Association)] (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - [Zavoico-Zimm] (Box 11, Folder 18)
- RU Children's School, 1963-1969; 3; 0.4 Cubic Feet
  Contains correspondence with parents; newsletters; meeting minutes; reports; expenditure statements; requisition forms; rules and regulations, and photos.
  - Expenditure Statements, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Expenditure Statements, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Meetings (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - [Miscellaneous], 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Parents (to-from), 1966-1968; folder 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Parents (to-from), 1968-1969; folder 2 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Reports (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Requisition Forms (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Rules and Regulations (Box 12, Folder 12)
- RU Concert Series, 1959-1976; 4; 1.4 Cubic Feet
  Contains correspondence with artists and talent agencies. Also includes informational brochures and publications regarding artists; Annual Reports; Subscription Brochures and lists; requisition forms; photos; sheet music; memorabilia (programs, promotional broadsides); and an index for the RU Concerts organized by artist, group, program and date.
  Arranged in chronological and in alphabetical order in one section.
  - RU Concert Programs, 1959-1966 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - RU Concert Programs, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - RU Concert Programs, 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - A, 1961-1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - B, 1961-1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - C, 1959-1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - D, 1961-1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - E, F (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - G (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - H (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - J (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - K (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - L (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - M (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - N, O, P, Q (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - R (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - S (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - (T-V) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - (W-Z) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - [Music Budgets], 1959-1966 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1959-1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1960 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - [Annual Concert Reports], 1960-1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - [RU Concerts-Miscellaneous], 1960-1975 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1960-1977 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1961-1968 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - [Metropolitan Opera], 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - [Subscription Brochures], 1962-1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - (Event "Dr. Miracle" - See RU Review May/June '65) Photos, 1965 May 8 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1965-1968 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - [Requisition Forms], 1965-1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - [Annual Subscriptions], 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - (Anders, Mariedi), 1966-1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - (Miscellaneous), 1966-1969 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - (Miscellaneous music files), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - (Miscellaneous music files), 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - (Miscellaneous), 1968 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - (Programs), 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - [Mariedi Anders Artists Management Inc.], 1972 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Music memorabilia (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - [Index to RU Concert: Artists / Groups / Date / Program] (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous drawing and sheet music (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Navy Department, 1932-1946; 5; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Contains reports from the Bureau of Aeronautics regarding Contract No. NXs-6875. Also includes reports, memoranda and notes regarding the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics.
  Arranged in chronological order by subject.
  - Report No. 1 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1942 June 6-August 5 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Report No. 1 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1942 June 6-August 5 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Bureau of Aeronautic s - Contract No. NXs-6875 Report No. 1, 1942 June 6-August 6 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Report No. 2 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1942 August 6-October 6 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Report No. 2 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1942 August 6-October 6 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Report No. 3 Contract No. NXs -6875, 1942 October 6-December 6 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Report No. 3 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1942 October 6-December 6 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Report No. 4, 1942 December 6-1943 February 6 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Report No. 5 Contract No. NXs-6875 (Fig. 2 lacking), 1943 February 6-April 6 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Report No. 5 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 February 6-April 6 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Report No. 6 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 April 6-June 6 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Report No. 6 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 April 6-June 6 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Report No. 7 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 June 6-August 14 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Report No. 7 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 June 6-August 14 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Report No. 8 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 August 14-October 8 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Report No. 9 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 October 8-December 14 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Report No. 10 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1943 December 14-1944 February 14 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Report No. 11 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1944 June 6 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Report No. 12 Contract No. NXs-6875, 1944 December 28 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Memorandum Report, 1945 November 2 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Memorandum Report, 1945 November 2 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Report No. 448, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Report No. 606, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Report No. 466, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Technical Memoranda, 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Advanced Restricted Report, 1942 1944 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Technical Notes, 1943 February (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Report No. IDS-9-41 "Determination of Effect of Speed on Measurement of Free Air Temperature", 1941 August 25 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Report No. IDS-38-42 "Report on the Determination of the Effect of Speed on Measurement of Free Air Temperature for Various Installation", 1942 September 28 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - "Report on Lead Resistance Effects on the Ratio Type Universal Thermometers", 1943 September 21 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Contract No. NXs-6875 from RIMR - (draft), 1945 June 20 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Contract No. NXs-6875 - from RIMR, 1945 June 20 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Contract No. NXs-6875 - from RIMR - (figure pages), 1945 June 20 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Contract No. NXs-6875 - from RIMR - (complete report), 1945 June 20 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Contract No. NXs-6875 - Correspondence and Notes, 1944-1946 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - [Bureau of Aeronautics - Contract No. NXs-6875 - Blueprints], 1945 May (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Bureau of Aeronautics - Copy of Contract No. NXs-6875, 1942 June 6 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics - Report No. 320 "The Measurement-of Fluctuations of Air Speed by the Hot-Wire Anemometer" (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript - "On the Convection of Heat from Small Cylinders in a Stream of Fluid: Determination of the Convection Constants of Small Platinum Wires with Applications to Hot-Wire Anemometry." - Louis Vessot King, 1914 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Notes on development of air speed instrument (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Navy Contract - Shedlovsky, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - [Bureau of Aerodynamics - Thermocouple Thermometer] (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - [Bureau of Aerodynamics - Thermocouple Thermometer], 1951 April 26 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Bureau of Aerodynamics - Patent Information, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Bureau of Aerodynamics - Aeronautical Instruments Laboratory, 1949 January 31 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Charge Sheets, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Shedlovsky Manuscripts, 1959-1972; 6; 0.9 Cubic Feet
  Contains both manuscripts by Shedlovsky and colleagues. These manuscripts include varying versions of a chapter on "Conductometry" for Physical Methods of Organic Chemistry including proofs, the first copy and the final draft. Includes topics such as conductometry, ionization, electrolytic conductance and electrophoresis.
  - Electrolytic Conductance - Corrections, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Conductometry: Determination of Rates of Reaction References (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Conductometry, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Conductometry: original copy, 1967 April; Headings pp. 1-40 and references & pp. 41-58 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Conductometry - 6/67 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Conductometry - 6/67-10/68 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Conductometry - Final Draft (Box 19, Folder 4)
    (See original for Figs. 1-14) carbon copy - 8/28/67.
  - Conductometry - 2/71 & 5/71 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Conductometry, 1972 August (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Conductometry - Chapter 3 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "The Effect of Valence on the Electrolytic Conductance of Salts" (Box 19, Folder 8)